Preliminary Inventory to the Communications Workers of America, District 1, New England Area Records WAG.312
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Communications Workers of America, District 1, New England Area Records
1960s-2000s (bulk, 1980s-2000s)
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Communications Workers of America. District 1
Bouchard, Paul
WAG.312
45.5 Linear Feet (46 boxes)
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Paul Bouchard, 2010. The accession number associated with this gift is 2010.059.
Conditions Governing Access
Series I: General Files is open for research without restrictions.
Series II: Grievances is closed for fifty years from the settlement of the grievance.
Historical/Biographical Note
Starting in the 1980s, the Communications Workers of America (CWA), District 1, New England Area supported CWA locals throughout New England with organizing, negotiations, grievances, and arbitrations. Initially led by area director Ed McCann, the New England Area included CWA Representatives William J. McKelligan, Michael L. Grieco, and Paul Bouchard. After staff reductions in the 2000s, District 1 closed its remaining office in Boston and relocated the remainder of the staff in 2010.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged into three series:
Series I: General Files, 1960s-2000s
Series II: Grievances, 1980s-2000s
Series III: Archived Website, 2009-ongoing
This collection is unprocessed.
Scope and Content Note
This collection consists of negotiations, agreements, arbitrations, and grievances from between telecommunications employers and CWA locals in Massachusetts and other parts of New England. Most of the files were created by CWA Representatives William J. McKelligan, Michael L. Grieco, and Paul Bouchard.
Grievances have been separated into Series II and are closed for fifty years after the resolution of the grievance.
Related Material at the Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Communications Workers of America, District 1 Records (WAG 117)
Communications Workers of America, Local 1250 Records (WAG 258)
Communications Workers of America Records (WAG 124)
Communications Workers of America Records: Addendum (WAG 124.1)
Custodial History
The archived website was migrated from the California Digital Library's Web Archiving Service to the Internet Archive's Archive-It Service in November 2015. The link to California Digital Library was removed in October 2017.
Labor unions |x Telecommunication |z Massachusetts.; Collective labor agreements -- Telecommunication.; Communications Workers of America. Local 1051; Communications Workers of America. Local 1250; NYNEX Corporation; Communications Workers of America. Local 1366; McKelligan, William J.; Bouchard, Paul; Grieco, Michael L.; Communications Workers of America; Communications Workers of America. Local 1302 (Lynn, Mass.); Communications Workers of America. Local 1301 (Braintree, Mass.); Communications Workers of America. Local 1365; AT & T (Firm); Communications Workers of America. District 1; Bouchard, Paul
- Series I: General Files, 1960s-2000s
  - Negotiations and Agreements, late 1980s-early 2000s (Box 1)
  - Negotiations with AT&T, Bell Atlantic, Verizon, and Massachusetts Towns (Carlisle, Concord, Littleton, and Westford), Arbitrations, and Agreements, early 1980s-early 2000s (Box 4)
  - Agreements and Arbitrations, early 1980s-early 2000s (Box 6)
  - Agreement Booklets from Various Locals (mostly in the Northeastern U.S.), circa early 1960s-mid 2000s (Box 7)
  - Negotiations, Agreements, and CWA National Meetings, 1992-1998 (Box 8)
  - Negotiations with Verizon, Correspondence, and Arbitrations, late 1980s-2003 (Box 9)
  - Local 1365 Agreements and Work Rules, early 1990s-early 2000s (Box 11)
  - AT&T: Strikes, Negotiations, and Arbitrations, 1983-mid 1990s (Box 12)
  - Negotiations, Agreements, and Arbitrations, early 1980s-early 2000s (Box 13)
  - Negotiations with AT&T, NYNEX, and Warner Cable, late 1980s-early 2000s (Box 14)
  - Negotiations and Agreements (mostly with Bell Atlantic and NYNEX) and Arbitrations, 1986-early 2000s (Box 15)
  - Arbitrations, Negotiations, and Agreements, early 1980s-2000 (Box 17)
  - Negotiations (mostly with AT&T), mid 1980s-early 2000s (Box 18)
  - Negotiations, Agreements, Arbitrations, and Correspondence, mid 1980s-early 2000s (Box 21)
  - Negotiations (mostly NYNEX), Agreements, and Arbitrations, 1964-late 1990s (Box 22)
  - Negotiations (Locals 1301 and 1302), Agreements, and Arbitrations, 1968-1989 (Box 24)
  - Negotiations and Agreements (mostly with NYNEX and AT&T), mid 1980s-early 2000s (Box 28)
  - Negotiations and Agreements (mostly AT&T), mid 1990s-late 1990s (Box 33)
  - Negotiations and Agreements (including between Bell Atlantic and Local 1301 and AT&T and Local 1366), 1989-2000 (Box 34)
  - Local 1301 Negotiations and Correspondence and NYNEX Agreement with Local 1395, 1983-1986 (Box 35)
  - Organizing, Negotiations, and Agreements, 2000s (Box 37)
  - Negotiations and Agreements with AT&T and CWA Water Bottle with Signatures, 1995-2003 (Box 41)
  - Negotiations and National CWA Meeting, late 1990s-early 2000s (Box 45)
- Series II: Grievances (CLOSED for 50 years after settlement of grievance), 1980s-2000s
  Conditions Governing Access
  Grievance files are closed for fifty years after the resolution of the grievance.
  - Grievances (mostly Locals 1301 and 1365) [CLOSED until 2037-2053], late 1980s-early 2000s (Box 2)
  - Grievances [CLOSED until 2033-2058], mid 1980s-2008 (Box 3)
  - Grievances [CLOSED until 2040-2053], early 1990s-early 2000s (Box 5)
  - Grievances [CLOSED until 2037-2057], late 1980s-mid 2000s (Box 10)
  - Locals 1365 and 1366 Grievances [CLOSED until 2040-2053], early 1990s-early 2000s (Box 16)
  - Local 1301 Grievances [CLOSED until 2030-2039], 1980s (Box 19)
  - Grievances [CLOSED until 2030-2053], early 1980s-early 2000s (Box 20)
  - Local 1366 Grievances [CLOSED until 2037-2053], mid 1980s-early 2000s (Box 23)
  - Grievances [CLOSED until 2040-2057], early 1990s-mid 2000s (Box 25)
  - Grievances [CLOSED until 2049-2056], 1999-2006 (Box 26)
  - Locals 1302 and 1365 Grievances [CLOSED until 2040-2053], early 1990s-early 2000s (Box 27)
  - Locals 1051, 1250, and 1365 Grievances [CLOSED until 2047-2057], late 1990s-mid 2000s (Box 29)
  - Grievances [CLOSED until 2037-2053], late 1980s-early 2000s (Box 30)
  - Locals 1301 and 1302 Grievances [CLOSED until 2040-2053], early 1990s-early 2000s (Box 31)
  - Grievances (mostly Locals 1301 and 1302) [CLOSED until 2037-2053], late 1980s-early 2000s (Box 32)
  - Grievances (mostly Local 1051) [CLOSED until 2030-2053], early 1980s-early 2000s (Box 36)
  - Locals 1301 and 1365 Grievances [CLOSED until 2030-2053], early 1980s-early 2000s (Box 38)
  - Locals 1051 and 1302 Grievances [CLOSED until 2043-2057], mid 1990s-mid 2000s (Box 39)
  - Locals 1301, 1302, and 1365 Grievances [CLOSED until 2040-2057], early 1990s-mid 2000s (Box 40)
  - Grievances [CLOSED until 2040-2057], early 1990s-mid 2000s (Box 42)
  - Grievances (mostly Local 1301) [CLOSED until 2033-2049], mid 1980s-late 1990s (Box 43)
  - Locals 1051, 1301, and 1302 Grievances [CLOSED until 2033-2049], mid 1980s-late 1990s (Box 44)
  - Grievances [CLOSED until 2040-2053], early 1990s-early 2000s (Box 46)
- Series III: Archived Website, Feb 26, 2009-ongoing
  Scope and Content Note
  District 1 of the Communications Workers of America (CWA) includes 327 CWA local unions in New York, New Jersey, New England, and eastern Canada. Members are employed in many different sectors of the economy including, telecommunications; health care; higher education; manufacturing; broadcast and cable television; commercial printing and newspapers; state, local, and country government. The website contains news listings, bargaining agreements, their political action committee, and event listings.
  Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
  Due to technical or privacy issues, archived websites may not be exact copies of the original website at the time of the web crawl. Certain file types will not be captured dependent on how they are embedded in the site. Other parts of websites that the crawler has difficulty capturing includes Javascript, streaming content, database-driven content, and highly interactive content. Full-Text searches of archived websites are available at https://archive-it.org/organizations/567.